uread.com 2012-12-13

# uRead.com: Buy Books Online: Bookstore in India: Highest Discount

###  My Account 

##  What is My Account?

“My Account” would help you view and update your account and orders any time. "My Account" allows you complete control over your transactions at uRead.com . You can 

  * Manage/edit all your personal data like address, phone numbers, email ids 
  * change your password 
  * track the status of your orders
  * check your Wishlist

###  Safe and Secure Shopping

##  Is it safe to use my credit card? 

Yes, shopping at uRead.com is 100% safe. Credit card payments are processed through the Axis Bank (formerly UTI Bank) payment gateway. Axis Bank is one of the biggest and most trusted banks in India. Internet Banking and other payments are processed by CCAvenue. We are also adding other payment gateways like PayPal which are the most secured gateways globally. Axis Bank uses the latest encryption technology to protect your credit card information. It encrypts your credit card number so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet. Furthermore, Axis Bank also asks you to enter the CVV (Credit Verification Value) number on your credit card. This is a 3 digit number which follows your credit card number and is given at the back of the card to ensure that the person entering the card number has the physical plastic card with him/her. You can be assured that uRead.com offers you the highest standards of security currently available on the Net so as to ensure that your shopping experience is private, safe and secure. 

##  Does uRead.com store my credit card information?

URead.com does not collect or store your credit card/bank account information at all. Axis Bank/CCAvenue authorizes the transaction directly without any information passing through us. 

###  Checking the Status of Your Order

##  How do I check the current status of my orders?

You can review the status and other information of all your orders, whether pending or fulfilled, that you have placed with URead.com. To check the status of your pending orders, click on the “My Account” link in the top right of any page on our store. This will take you to your My Account page, where you can click on the “My Orders” link to view the status of all orders. To view the status of a specific order, click on the “Order Number”. After your order is shipped out from our warehouse, we will send you a mail with the shipping details. 

##  What do the different order status mean ?

_Payment Pending Authorization:_ Your order has been logged and we are waiting for authorization from the payment gateway.  
_Payment Authorized, Order under Processing :_ We have received authorization from the payment gateway and are processing your order.   
_Order Shipped:_ Your order has been shipped out of our warehouse and and is on its way to the shipping address provided by you.   
_Order Cancelled: The order was cancelled._

##  When and how can I cancel an order ?

You can cancel your order before it reaches the "Order shipped" state. You can do so by sending us an email via our Contact Us Form with the order number.

###  Payments 

##  Credit Card Payments:

We accept all VISA and MasterCard, both Indian and International. Click on the "BUY" button and select "Pay By Credit Card" on the following page. To use American Express Cards please choose the "Pay by Net banking" option. 

##  Debit Cards:

We accept Debit Cards issued by the following banks: 

  * AXIS Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * Barclays Bank (VISA Electron only)
  * Canara Bank 
  * Citibank 
  * Corporation Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * Cosmos Bank Visa (VISA Electron only)
  * Deutsche Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * HDFC Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * ICICI Bank
  * Indian Overseas Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * ING Vyasa Bank (VISA Electron only)
  * Karur Vysya Bank (VISA Electron only) 
  * Kotak Mahindra Bank Virtual Card (VISA Electron only)
  * Punjab National Bank 
  * Standard Chartered Bank Visa (VISA Electron only)
  * State Bank of India 
  * Union Bank of India

##  Internet Banking:

We accept payment through Internet Banking for the following banks: 

  * ABN AMRO Bank 
  * AXIS Bank 
  * Bank of Baroda Corporate Accounts
  * Bank of Baroda Retail Accounts
  * Bank Of India 
  * Bank Of Maharashtra 
  * Bank Of Rajasthan 
  * Citibank Bank Account Online 
  * City Union Bank 
  * Corporation Bank 
  * Deutsche Bank 
  * Federal Bank
  * HDFC Direct Pay 
  * ICICI Bank 
  * IDBI Bank 
  * IndusInd Bank 
  * Jammu & Kashmir Bank 
  * Karnataka Bank 
  * Karur Vysya Bank 
  * Kotak Mahindra Bank 
  * Lakshmi Vilas Bank NetBanking
  * Oriental Bank Of Commerce 
  * Punjab National Bank Corporate Accounts
  * Punjab National Bank Retail Accounts
  * South Indian Bank
  * State Bank Of India 
  * State Bank of Indore 
  * State Bank of Travancore 
  * Syndicate Bank 
  * Union Bank Of India 
  * Vijaya Bank 
  * YES BANK 

##  Payments by Demand Draft/Cheque/Money Order:

You can make the DD or Cheque in favour of "Prakash eSolutions Pvt. Ltd. " payable at par in Delhi and send it to us at the address given below: 

URead.com  
Prakash eSolutions Pvt. Ltd.  
113A, Darya Ganj,  
Bharat Scout Guide Building  
New Delhi 110002, INDIA  
Phone : +91-11-43501212 

In case of cheque payments, orders will be processed only after clearance of the cheque. We accept cheques which are payable "at par" at New Delhi. Do make sure that your book is NOT shown as Out of Stock on uRead.com before you send us your payment. 

If the value of your order is less that $1.84, add $0.55 as shipping charges. We will process your order upon receiving your payment and your book will be couriered to you, or sent by Government Registered Post if there is no Courier Service operational in your area. 

Enclose a covering letter with the name and author of the book, **your Shipping Address, Phone Number and Email Address.** Kindly also send us an email informing us that you have sent your DD/Cheque. It will help us process your order quicker. 

For payments through Money Orders, send them to the address mentioned above. Please intimate us in advance before sending the Money Order. 

##  Payment by Cash on Delivery (COD) Order in India: 

##  What is Cash On Delivery?

Cash On Delivery **(COD)** is a payment option offered to you wherein you order the Book(s) on uRead and pay at your doorstep on delivery. The Cash will be collected by our Representative Courier partner delivering the Book(s). 

##  Which Book(s) can be ordered by COD payment option?

The Book(s) which can be ordered by the COD option, will have a small Icon displayed/ COD mentioned in Payment options. 

##  Is COD available for my destination?

Currently, we are offering COD payment option to more than 2000 Pin Codes **in India only**. (See details/list of locations covered) 

Enter your shipping address pincode | *  
  |   
---|---|---  
Enter your shipping address city  | *  
  |   

##  Do I have to pay any extra charges for availing the COD payment option? 

No. When you choose to order by COD at uRead, you do not have to pay any extra charges. Please do **NOT** pay more than the order value of the Book(s) when they reach you.   
However, in a rare case or eventuality, in case the delivery person of the Representative Courier partner insists for any additional amount (Delivery charges, Octroi, Taxes etc.), please pay and take a receipt. And **INFORM** us immediately and we will refund you with the ‘extra’ Amount you have paid. 

##  What is the process/How do I place the COD orders?

Cash On Delivery payment option is currently available in India only.

The process – 

  * Choose the Book(s) you wish to order from uRead by using the ‘Add to cart’ option.
  * After clicking on ‘Checkout’ – please verify the titles & quantities; and click on ‘Proceed to checkout’.
  * If you already have an Account, ‘Login’ using your Email and Password. If not, please create your uRead.com New Account using your Email ID & and Password; and ‘Login’.
  * Enter your shipping address and click on ‘Save and use this address’. 
  * On choosing the COD mode of payment (on the right hand side), your order will be created and an Order Confirmation mail with the Order no. will be sent to your Email ID. 
  * On delivery of your Book(s), please pay the Cash amount as required.

In case of any assistance, you may call back at +91-11-43501212 or mail at [customerservice@uread.com](mailto:customerservice@uread.com). 

##  Other Terms and Conditions

  * Cheques/Demand Drafts/Money orders will not be accepted once you choose to pay by COD.
  * Delivery of orders will be done Address specific and not person specific 
  * The maximum order value for COD is Rs. 50,000
  * Discount Coupons for extra discounts can be availed while using the COD option.
  * In case of Returns under the COD option, the refunds will be made vide Pay Order/Demand Drafts. Standard Returns policy will apply for other deductions, if any.

##  Any other question?

If you have any other query pertaining to COD payment option, please contact us at [support@uread.com](mailto:support@uread.com)

##  Contact Us 

Couldn't find the information you needed? Please ask on [ contact@uRead.com](mailto:contact@uRead.com) .

###  Shipping

##  How much are the shipping charges?

URead.com provides free shipping on all books to all locations in India if your total order amount is more than $1.84. Otherwise $0.55 is charged as shipping charge. 

International shipping rates are calculated based on the product and the shipping location. These rates are made available during checkout once you enter the delivery address. 

##  What is the estimated delivery time within India?

The estimated time of delivery is mentioned on every Book's page as for shipping within India. It may differ from one book to another. Please read below for an explanation of delivery estimates: 

**Books mentioned as 3 days delivery time:** These books will also be mentioned as "In Stock" on the book page. For all areas serviced by reputed couriers the delivery time will be 3 business days. For other areas books will be sent by Registered Book Post through the Indian Postal Service which may take 1-2 weeks depending on the location. Business days exclude public holidays and Sundays. Also note that this doesn't apply to bulk orders.

**Books mentioned as more than 3 days delivery time:** We procure and ship the books within the time specified on the book detail page. Some of the books have to be imported from outside India. These books are sometimes mentioned as "Imported Edition" on the book page and can take 10 or more days to reach you. You can always rest assured that you will receive the book that you have ordered within the time specified on the book detail page. 

**For Out of Stock books:** Currently we do not have these books available for sale. Please use the "Notify Me" feature and we will let you know once the book is available for sale at URead.com. 

With every order, you will receive an email containing the details of the order placed by you. Once the book(s) are shipped, you will receive another email containing the shipping details. 

##  What about other taxes and levies like sales tax, octroi etc.?

What you see is what you pay. Our prices are all inclusive. All taxes are included with the list prices. 

##  Do you ship internationally? 

Yes. We ship to all locations in India as well as countries such as - 

  * United States
  * Canada
  * United Kingdom
  * Australia
  * New Zealand
  * United Arab Emirates

...and many more.

We are continuously expanding the list of countries that we ship to. On special requests we will ship to other countries so please contact us on [ sales@uRead.com](mailto:sales@uRead.com)

##  Where's My Stuff?

The most current summary for all your orders is always available in "My Account" page. 

###  Returns

##  What do I do in case I receive a defective/damaged book from uRead.com?

We follow strict quality controls for packaging and shipping to our customers. If something is wrong with the books being shipped by uRead.com, we certainly want to help you. 

**_India_**  
If a book ordered by you on uRead is delivered to you in a damaged/defective condition, please email the pictures of the same at the time of opening the packet on [returns@uread.com](mailto:returns@uread.com) for a replacement and send the damaged book back to us. On receipt of the book, we’ll immediately send you the replacement copy and also compensate you for the costs incurred in sending the same to our office. If the book is not available in stock, you would be also eligible for an immediate refund. 

**_International_**  
In an exceptional case of you receiving a damaged / defective book, please do email the pictures at the time of opening the packet on [returns@uread.com](mailto:returns@uread.com) and we’ll take up on a case to case basis. 

##  How can I return a product ordered from uRead.com?

To provide you a worry free shopping experience on uRead.com, we offer you a No Questions Asked Return Policy. 

**_India_**  
In case you don’t require the book(s) ordered by you, please notify us about the same on [returns@uread.com](mailto:returns@uread.com) within 48 hours of receiving your shipment. You may return any unopened book(s) in its original packaging, for a refund or Gift Certificate for the amount. However, in this case, we’ll not be able to compensate the Shipping costs incurred by you. 

**_International_**  
We do not offer Returns on International shipments. 

###  URead.com Privacy Policy

We value the trust you place in uRead.com. That's why we insist upon the highest standards for secure transactions and customer information privacy. Please read the following statement to learn about our information gathering and dissemination practices. Note: Our privacy policy is subject to change at any time without notice. To make sure you are aware of any changes, please review this policy periodically. 

  1. ##  Collection of Personally Identifiable Information

We collect personally identifiable information (email address, name, phone number, etc.) from you when you set up a free account with uRead.com. While you can browse some sections of our site without being a registered member, certain activities (such as placing an order) do require registration. We do use your contact information to send you offers based on your previous orders and your interests. 

  2. ##  Use of Demographic and Profile Data

We use personal information to provide the services you request. To the extent we use your personal information to market to you, we will provide you the ability to opt-out of such uses. We use your personal information to resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote a safe service; collect fees owed; measure consumer interest in our products and services, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our terms and conditions; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. In our efforts to continually improve our product and service offerings, we collect and analyze demographic and profile data about our users' activity on our website. We identify and use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. We will occasionally ask you to complete optional online surveys. These surveys may ask you for contact information and demographic information (like postal code, zip code, age, or income level). We use this data to tailor your experience at our site, providing you with content that we think you might be interested in--and to display content according to your preferences.   
**Cookies**  
A "cookie" is a small piece of information stored by a Web server on a Web browser so it can be later read back from that browser. Cookies are useful for enabling the browser to remember information specific to a given user. uRead.com places both permanent and temporary cookies in your computer's hard drive. uRead.com's cookies do not contain any of your personally identifiable information. 

  3. ##  Sharing of personal information

We may share personal information with our other corporate entities and affiliates to: help detect and prevent identity theft, fraud and other potentially illegal acts; correlate related or multiple accounts to prevent abuse of our services; and to facilitate joint or co-branded services that you request where such services are provided by more than one corporate entity. Those entities and affiliates may not market to you as a result of such sharing unless you explicitly opt-in. We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. We may disclose personal information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners, or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms or Privacy Policy; respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party; or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the general public. uRead.com and its affiliates will share some or all of your personal information with another business entity should we (or our assets) plan to merge with, or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a transaction occur, that other business entity (or the new combined entity) will be required to follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. 

  4. ##  Links to Other Sites

Our site links to other websites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. uRead.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites. 

  5. ##  Security Precautions

Our site has stringent security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Whenever you change or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. Once your information is in our possession we adhere to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access. 

  6. ##  Choice/Opt-Out

uRead.com provides all users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving non-essential (promotional, marketing-related) communications from us on behalf of our partners, and from us in general, after setting up an account. 

  7. ##  Advertisements on URead.com

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

  8. ##  Questions?

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the following address:
